Good morning, Church.
[Good morning.]
You are very good in receiving prayer but you are not good after the prayer.
Tell your neighbour, "You are a good Christian in receiving but after receiving, a very bad Christian".
I'm telling you.
Can you see the way you have been dancing?
And now you sit quietly.
You are very good in waiting upon the Lord but when the Lord now comes,
you are not good when God leaves.
Once you are touched, it must be followed by absolute trust in God that He is now working out the answer -
no more anxiety or worry as if you never prayed at all.
Before you are touched, you know what you prayed for.
Once you are touched - absolute trust.
In whom?
In that process, there is no anxiety, worry or tension.
Leave it for God once you are touched.
But if, after the touching, you are still worried as if you had never prayed at all, it is a waste.
Such a touch is a waste.
Christians all over the world today only know how to ask for prayer
but after the prayer they don't know what to do next.
That is why you see them fall into anxiety and full of worry as if they never prayed at all.
You have diabetes, and the doctor had given you a tablet you must take regularly,
and you are here in The SCOAN sitting down with the tablet inside your pocket
because anything can happen.
You believe you would collapse without your tablet.
You are holding your tablet.
After the prayer, you begin to ask yourself, "Would I use my tablet again, or should I not use my tablet?"
I need to see the man of God and ask him whether I should still use my tablet or not.
Let me tell you what Jesus says.
Jesus says if you don't trust Him with your tablets, you can never trust Him without your tablets.
If you don't trust Jesus with your tablets, you cannot trust Him without your tablets.
It is a wisdom - a deep one.
Eighty percent of us sitting here have a tablet in the pocket.
Hypertension - a very common condition.
When I was touching a man there, he fell down; his hypertension tablet dropped on the floor.
You know what happened?
When he fell down, immediately I left the place, he collected back his tablet.
He quickly run.
I was looking.
The first thing he did after standing up was grabbing his tablet and putting it in his pocket.
Why?
"In case I'm not healed."
"I don't want to die."
You know it is very difficult to trust something you receive for free.
Something you receive for free is the most difficult thing to trust.
A man just looks at you and says, "I give you this Laser Jeep of 25 million".
"I don't know this man. I have never met him before and he gives me this!"
You can never believe.
You only believe someone whom you have served, in one way or another -
he's sent you for an errand, you have done something for him in the past, you have helped him in the past.
If he gives you such a Laser Jeep, you cannot doubt it.
When Jesus heals you, He heals you perpetually, freely.
It is always difficult to believe, compared to where you spent millions, a fortune.
But when Jesus just touches and heals you, it is always difficult to believe.
It takes the grace of God.
Take this proverb - it will help you.
If you cannot trust Jesus with your tablets, you cannot trust Him without your tablets.
There is a way Jesus does things.
It is not you that would ask Jesus whether you should use the tablet or not.
If you don't believe Him with your tablets, you cannot believe Him without the tablets.
If Jesus doesn't want you to use it again, you will just naturally forget it - it will be absent.
The following days you will not remember taking your tablets - you will naturally forget it.
That is how Jesus works.
Jesus has a way of working.
If you understand me - let me see your hand.
Look, something you take regularly; something will remind you -
it is either your blood pressure that rises, having headache, having a dry tongue,
or you find yourself going frequently to the toilet.
There are many signs that would remind you that you have to take your tablets.
But in this case, you just forget your tablet because your life seems to be normal.
After some days you realise that you have not been taking your tablets.
It is Jesus that is working.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
He has the ability to block the sense of your memory if all the symptoms you had cease.
It is when there are symptoms - your body is warm, you have headache, your throat is dry, you cannot sleep -
that will remind you about your drugs.
Healing does not just come without a message.
Healing and deliverance come with a message.
If you have not been grounded in the Word and you receive healing, you will likely loose the healing.
Tell your neighbour.
If you have not been grounded in the Word of healing and you receive healing,
you are likely to lose the healing.
That is, if you have not received a message concerning that healing.
Message is maintenance.
It is like giving you a car without teaching you how to maintain it.
You just received a car, a brand new car, and you are ignorant about maintenance - how to wash the car,
how to change the tyres - you don't know anything about it.
It means that this vehicle will soon knock down.
You must have thorough knowledge of how to maintain that vehicle.
You must be grounded in the Word to maintain healing, salvation and deliverance.
The top challenge we are facing is simple.
I make the Word first place.
I exalt the Word of God.
I make it first place.
I make my schedule around the Word of God.
Your practice has not been like that; that is why it is difficult for you to trust in God's Word.
I take it first place; I exalt the Word.
I disagree, I agree.
I agree with the Word of God and I disagree with any condition, situation or circumstances
that are contrary to the Word.
I disagree.
I agree with the Word of God; I choose to agree.
But when you are making your schedule, you don’t carry God along.
You have already prepared your schedule for today.
When you leave here, you are going to a meeting, you must leave here at such time...
You don't carry God along.
We have not been grounded.
When we are grounded in the Word, we take it first place.
You exalt the Word.
How do we wait and believe that He is working out the answer?
How can we wait without worrying again over the situation?
When a man of God says, "You are healed, in Jesus' name", you say, "Amen" -
you would then worry and be anxious, as if you had never prayed at all.
This is a message you need to receive now.
If not, you will keep losing your healing by ignorance.
Why to receive it, if you keep losing it?
Because that worry alone nullifies your blessing.
You say, "Man of God, I have a headache".
I say, "Be healed, in Jesus' name."
I turn back and immediately you start wondering if you are healed now.
That statement alone nullifies that healing.
When you begin to compare places, where you spent millions to receive healing and you did not receive it,
with a place where somebody would just touch you and say, "You are healed".
"No, I don't know - this kind of healing - I don't know."
That nullifies immediately what you received.
If it is God, it is freedom and it is free.
Tell your neighbour,
"If it is God, it is freedom and it is free".
But if it is man, you have to labour for it and pay with your sweat.
So, this is what we don't know; the things of God are a mystery.
That what you receive is free does not call for questioning or doubt, it is God!
We don't need to struggle to believe.
Faith comes spontaneously, just naturally.
But today, we keep on struggling to believe.
You have to read Psalm 35 three times.
You wake up at midnight, you have your Bible under the pillow.
You set your alarm to wake up to say, "Thank You, Jesus".
"He is alive, Amen..."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We don't need to struggle to believe.
Believing is natural.
Many of your children abandoned your house in the past.
They abandoned their families saying that their father is a drunkard.
They say they are born-again.
You could not find them but now suddenly, they are back to the world.
When you are struggling to believe, you will still come back to the world.
When you are struggling to accept Jesus, you will soon leave Jesus.
Tell your neighbour,
"If you struggle to believe Jesus, you will soon leave Jesus".
A good example: You lock a brother or sister who is a smoker or a drug-addict inside the house -
"You are not going to smoke or drink today".
You lock your son inside the house.
You say he must fast for three days.
It is not from his (heart).
It is not from his heart - to fast.
You know they are very tough.
You observe him now.
You have been telling him that he is a drug-addict.
You ask him to follow you to the church.
He says, "No, I am not going to church".
Any time you go to church, he would go to the club.
One day you set it up and call your pastor.
You deceive him and lock the gate.
Your pastor is there and says, "Three days fasting".
He says, "Please, I do not want to fast".
You say, "You must fast".
You have tried everything to force him to be delivered.
No, it is not possible.
Why are you telling him to come to church while he refuses?
You can pray for him and ask God to touch him.
Whilst he is in the night club smoking, he will just leave that place one day.
It could be caused by headache or something that happened, and it will bring him home.
After some time, he will come to his senses and say, "Mummy, I am sorry - I am tired of this life".
He will not know that it is because of your prayer.
Then, you take it up from there.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Many of us have tried it in the past.
You struggled to believe, but with time, it became worse in our righteousness.
We don't trouble to believe.
Belief is natural and spontaneous.
Let me tell you: When you work hard to get something and you cannot get that thing, it is very frustrating.
You work, you labour, and at the end of the day you cannot achieve that - it is very frustrating.
But when you don't work hard, you leave it naturally...
Look at what I said:
Work as if everything depends on you and pray as if everything depends on God.
Things of God are a decision.
You just sit down and say, "God, I am tired of my former life. I want to take a new life".
It is simple.
Make a decision and start your prayer from there.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Our relationship with God – this is a question of the heart.
In our heart, whom do we trust?
When we start praying now, you will begin to move your body.
How do we know that your heart is also moving like that?
If I say, "Amen", and all of you say, "Amen"; it is not all of you that say "Amen".
In truth and faith, before you can say, "Amen", you must believe with all your heart.
We do not serve our God with our hearts again.
Our relationship with God – this is a question of the heart.
In our heart, whom do we trust?
If you know that, you will begin to get it right - because we are getting it wrong.
No matter how educated you are, if you apply your education to serve God, you get it wrong.
The person you trust in your heart is your god.
Whether it is a tree, palm oil or water - this is your god.
You say, "He is alive, Amen" - you keep saying that to God, whereas in your heart you don't trust God.
The person you trust in your heart is your god, not the person you worship.
Faith is of man's heart; faith is a heart that believes in God.
So, whom you trust in your heart is your god.
We don’t trust two things with our heart but with our body, our confession, we can trust a million things.
With our heart, there is just one thing we trust.
If you have been trusting God with all your heart, God will be only, not one of those things.
When you plan to attend different events following your visit in the church - you are "comparing" God.
God should not be compared with anything.
If you have trusted God with all your heart, you will not compare Him.
You can never compare anything with what you trust with your heart.
With your mouth and confession, you can trust thousands of things
but with your heart, there is only one thing you can trust.
What you trust with your heart can move you from this place, as we are talking now.
If you receive a phone call, "Hello. That million dollars is ready now",
you would just ask your neighbour, "Where is usher here?"
They say, "This man is an usher".
"I am pressed."
Because we know how to lie.
If we want something, we can lie within a second.
Immediately you ask your colleague to help you, "I am pressed".
You may even say, "I have diabetes".
It is because you want to leave this place immediately.
They will now rush to call an usher for you.
You will not be the one to talk.
People will want to help you.
They will say, "Help this man. He is pressed".
In order to get your way, you will now walk like this until you get to the restroom.
The usher will show you, "This is the toilet".
"OK, thank you."
You will lock yourself there.
You will now call the man back, "You mean, what is ready? Because I couldn't hear you well.
T.B. Joshua was talking. There was so much noise".
Whereas you heard him well but you would like to hear it again, so it will gladden your heart.
"I said the 2 million dollars are ready. You can come immediately to sign the cheque
because I will be travelling to the UK this evening".
"OK - now!
Give me 2 minutes."
You will just rush out now.
You will abandon your car - a bike is very fast.
You have not been using bike for so long.
You just take a bike, you abandon your car, your wife and children.
You take a bike.
You call your wife, "Wait for me in the church. You may need to sleep there when they close."
That is the person you trust with all your heart.
What is that?
Money.
You can betray anything for the person you trust with your heart.
If you trust God with all your heart, your life would be better than this.
You cannot compare God with anything, once you trust Him with all your heart.
We are here today.
You say you trust God.
Even people who came from other countries - if there had been a phone call before you left,
that this contract, for which you had been looking for a long time, was ready to be executed,
you would have postponed your journey.
For you it is a matter of buying a new ticket and this contract would bring more money.
You postpone it till...
What you trust with your heart is only.
You don’t compare anything with what you trust with your heart.
You just have to begin to trust God with all your heart today.
Heart is a place where you cannot trust two things; it’s not possible.
It is not possible to trust both God and money in your heart.
That is heart for you.
You can confess, "Jesus is Lord", and confess other things at the same time,
but in the heart, only one thing is allowed to work there.
So, your relationship with God is a question of the heart.
In your heart, whom do you trust?